Guide to the Cynthia Macdonald Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Cynthia Macdonald Papers
1867-2005
1965-2000
03/2010-019
Macdonald, Cynthia
54.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The collection contains typed and handwritten drafts of poems and other writings, as well as correspondence, photographs, clippings, and memorabilia related to Cynthia Macdonald’s life and work as an accomplished poet and co-founder of the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston.
Biographical Information:
Cynthia Lee Macdonald was born in New York City in 1928 to Leonard Lee and Dorothy Kiam Lee. Significantly, her younger sister Virginia, to whom Cynthia was very close in age, died of scarlet fever at 5 or 6 years old. Macdonald’s parents divorced in 1940 and both eventually remarried. Leonard, a Hollywood scriptwriter for movies and television, lived in Los Angeles, while Dorothy returned to New York; Macdonald spent time on both coasts throughout her childhood and teen years.
Macdonald earned her Bachelor’s degree from Bennington College in Vermont in 1950. She married E.C. Macdonald in 1954 and had two children, Jennifer and Scott. Her budding career as an opera singer gave way to her poetry writing, prompting her enrollment at Sarah Lawrence College in New York to earn her Master’s degree in writing in 1970.
A career as a writing teacher soon followed. After teaching first at Sarah Lawrence College, then at Johns Hopkins University, she co-founded with Stanley Plumly the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston in 1979. She taught at UH until her retirement in the mid-2000s, receiving the Esther Farfel Award for faculty excellence along the way.
Macdonald became a widely published and award-winning poet. Her first of seven books of poetry, Amputations, was published in 1972, and she had individual poems published in dozens and dozens of esteemed magazines and journals such at The New Yorker, The Paris Review, and The Yale Review. Among the many honors and awards that Macdonald received for her writing were a Guggenheim Fellowship and the O.B. Hardison, Jr. Poetry Prize.
Macdonald was also a practicing psychoanalyst for many years, and a faculty member of the Houston-Galveston Psychoanalytic Institute.
Though born in New York, Cynthia Macdonald comes from old Houston stock: Her mother Dorothy was born in Houston in 1906 to Edward Kiam and Fanny Tim Kiam. The Kiam family had been in the city as far back as the mid-to-late 1800s. In 1893, Edward Kiam opened a clothing store in downtown Houston in a five-story brick building that still stands and is still known as “The Kiam Building” at 320 Main Street.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston -- Faculty; University of Houston. Creative Writing Program
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Diaries; Manuscripts (document genre); Memorabilia; Photocopies; Photographs; Poems; Typescripts
Personal Name:
Macdonald, Cynthia
Topical Term:
Authors, American; Authors, American -- 20th century; Poets, American; Poets, American -- 20th century
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
The book collection from Cynthia Macdonald’s personal library (http://library.uh.edu/search~S11/?searchtype=a&searcharg=Library+of+Cynthia+Macdonald&searchscope=11&sortdropdown=-&SORT=D&extended=1&SUBMIT=Search&searchlimits=&searchorigarg=aLibrary+of+Cynthia+Macdonald)
Scope and Contents
The collection contains typed and handwritten drafts of poems and other writings, as well as correspondence, photographs, clippings, and memorabilia related to Cynthia Macdonald’s life and work as an accomplished poet and co-founder of the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston. In addition to the extensive accumulation of multiple drafts of her writings, Macdonald’s trove of correspondence is of particular interest, featuring letters to and from writing friends, colleagues, and family members. The collection as a whole also documents Macdonald’s teaching career, psychoanalysis career, personal life, and family history.
The collection is divided into ten series: Writing; Correspondence; Writing Career; Writings by Others; Teaching Career; Psychoanalysis Career; Personal; Audiovisual; Electronic Media; and Family History. The Writing series and Correspondence series are thoroughly processed in detail, while the remaining series are arranged in accordance with minimal processing standards to expedite their availability to researchers. Each series is prefaced by a detailed description.
Detailed List of Contents
- Writing
  The Writing Series is the most robust series of the collection, comprising Cynthia Macdonald’s written works in various genres. The material includes typescripts, handwritten drafts, printed materials, and photocopies of published pieces. The series is divided into seven sub-series: Poetry; Fiction; Nonfiction; Autobiography; Journals, Diaries, and Dreams; Psychoanalysis; and Other Writings. (Further description of each sub-series is provided in the corresponding section below.) Wherever possible, folders are labeled according to Macdonald’s own organization.
  - Poetry
    Cynthia Macdonald generally organized her poetry files into four categories: Poems Collected in Books; Individual Poems; Poetry Fragments and Untitled Poems; and Poetry Ideas and Research. Some overlap is evident from one section to the next, as Macdonald filed multiple copies of her poems into different categories. Folders include typescript, edited drafts, handwritten copies, printed materials, and photocopies of published works.
    - Poems Collected in Books
      Titles of books are arranged in order of publication, from earliest to latest. Poems within each book are arranged in the same order of appearance as in the table of contents.
      - Amputations
        - The Platform Builders (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Objets D’Art (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Inventory (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - Consultation (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - Piranesi’s Pirandello (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - A Family of Dolls’ House Dolls (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Transfer (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Uncovering (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Coupling (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Summer Letter; Fall Letter; Winter Letter (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - The Inside Story (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - A Family Question (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Instructions from Bly (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Richard’s Book and Chopper Ganz (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Reply to the Request from the Remaining Poet for Suicide Suggestions (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - Riddle (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Eight for Luncheon (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - Breaking Seals (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - Guide to the Runes (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - Al Fried (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Past Ordering (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Aspects of Unicorns (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Paintings from the Slaughterhouse: A Slide Show of Hogs (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - The Insatiable Baby (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - One in a Velvet Glove (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - Refusing Further Risk (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - Reflections in Stone (Box 1, Folder 27)
        - Twice Too Long (Box 1, Folder 28)
        - The Holy Man Walks through Fire (Box 1, Folder 29)
        - Departure (Box 1, Folder 30)
        - Another Attempt at the Trick (Box 1, Folder 31)
        - Amputations: notes on the Table of Contents (Box 1, Folder 32)
        - Amputations manuscript (Box 1, Folder 33-35)
      - Pruning the Annuals
        - Pruning the Annuals manuscript (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Transplants
        - The Stained Glass Woman (Box 1, Folder 37)
        - Mistress Mary Quite Contrary (Box 1, Folder 38)
        - Getting to the End (Box 1, Folder 39)
        - The Stained Glass Man (Box 1, Folder 40)
        - The Horns of Forgetfulness (Box 1, Folder 41)
        - A Suspense Story (Box 1, Folder 42)
        - A Step toward Burial (Box 1, Folder 43)
        - The Amherst, Houston, New York Triangle (Box 1, Folder 44)
        - Direction (Box 1, Folder 45)
        - The Doctor Dimity Poems (Box 1, Folder 46)
        - Birthday Message (Box 1, Folder 47)
        - A Story for a Child (Box 1, Folder 48)
        - Difficult Revision (Box 1, Folder 49)
        - Accomplishments (Box 1, Folder 50)
        - News of the Death of the World’s Biggest Man (Box 1, Folder 51)
        - Innard Life (Box 1, Folder 52)
        - In Preparation (Box 1, Folder 53)
        - Jason of Whom I Am a Part (Box 1, Folder 54)
        - Severance Pay (Box 1, Folder 55)
        - Inheritance (Box 1, Folder 56)
        - A Discreet Plot (Box 1, Folder 57)
        - Investiture (Box 1, Folder 58)
        - The Late Mother (Box 1, Folder 59)
        - Thanksgiving in Cambridge, N.Y. (Box 1, Folder 60)
        - The Eel as the Letter E (Box 1, Folder 61)
        - Turning (Box 1, Folder 62)
        - Making It Up (Box 1, Folder 63)
        - The Story of My Detached Retina and Its Effects (Box 1, Folder 64)
        - The Present (Box 1, Folder 65)
        - A Given (Box 1, Folder 66)
        - Looking into My Father’s House (Box 1, Folder 67)
        - Poems removed from Transplants (Box 1, Folder 68)
        - Transplants manuscript (Box 1, Folder 69-77)
      - (W)holes
        - Francis Bacon (1561-1626; 1910- ), the Inventor of Spectacles, Is the Ringmaster (Box 1, Folder 78)
        - The World’s Fattest Dancer (Box 1, Folder 79)
        - The Mother of the Sun (Box 1, Folder 80)
        - The Siamese Sextuplets (Box 1, Folder 81)
        - Celebrating the Freak (Box 1, Folder 82)
        - The Kilgore Rangerette Whose Life Was Ruined (Box 1, Folder 83)
        - How to Order a Freak: (Box 1, Folder 84)
        - The Secrets of E. Munch (Box 1, Folder 85)
        - Florence Nightengale’s Parts (Box 1, Folder 86)
        - A Certain Sense of Awe (Box 1, Folder 87)
        - A Place to Watch the Birds (Box 1, Folder 88)
        - It Is Dangerous to Be the Conductor (Box 1, Folder 89)
        - Wanted: (Box 1, Folder 90)
        - The Lady Pitcher (Box 1, Folder 91)
        - Beads in a Red Box (Box 1, Folder 92)
        - The Dangers of Looking Back (Box 1, Folder 93)
        - Containing (Box 1, Folder 94)
        - The Lobster (Box 1, Folder 95)
        - The Conception (Box 1, Folder 96)
        - The Mosaic Hunchback (Box 1, Folder 97)
        - Burying the Babies (Box 1, Folder 98)
        - Burying the Babies (Box 1, Folder 99)
        - (W)holes manuscript (Box 1, Folder 100)
        - (W)holes manuscript, copyedited (Box 1, Folder 101)
        - (W)holes galley proofs (Box 1, Folder 102-103)
      - Alternate Means of Transport
        - Alternate Means of Transport (poem) drafts (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
        - Alternate Means of Transport (poem) drafts with comments (Box 2, Folder 3)
        - Alternate Means of Transport (poem) with peer edits/comments (Box 2, Folder 4)
        - The Tune He Saw (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - Why Penelope Was Happy (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - Degrees of Pen/man/ship (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Death on the High Seas (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - The Four Virginias (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - A Perfect Binding (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - The Erythrophobic Man (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Those Who Live Alone (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - Supplanting the Beloved (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - Apartments on First Avenue (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Tracking the Connections (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - In Such an Unhappy Neighborhood, Carlos (Box 2, Folder 16)
        - Wedding Bans: January 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        - By the Sea (Box 2, Folder 18)
        - My Familiar Lover (Box 2, Folder 19)
        - Hymn in a Bed of Amherst (Box 2, Folder 20)
        - Letter to Richard from Budapest (Box 2, Folder 21)
        - Postcard of Child Peeking out from under Its Mother’s Skirt (Box 2, Folder 22)
        - Knock, Knock (Box 2, Folder 23)
        - The River Honey Queen Bess (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - Serial Rescue (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Two Brothers in a Field of Absence (Box 2, Folder 26)
        - Alternate Means of Transport manuscript (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Living Wills
        - The Precise Shape of a Wave (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - A Past-Due Notice (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - Vain Remedy (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - Separations (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - The Murderer’s Daughter (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - Envy of Old Husbands (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - A Certain Distinction (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - The Sounding Cataract (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - Prayer for the Deserving (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - And Cause His Countenance to Shine upon You (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - A Critical Age (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - For a Friend Whose Son Drowned (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - Accidental Causes (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - Rose Magpie and Magpie Rose (Box 2, Folder 41)
        - At the Round Earth’s Imagined Corners (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - The Triborough Bridge a Crown for His Head (Box 2, Folder 43)
        - Living Wills: Table of Contents and notes (Box 2, Folder 44)
        - Living Wills manuscript (Box 2, Folder 45-46)
        - Living Wills page proofs (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - I Can’t Remember
        - Children Who Fall off the Edge of the World Because of Secrets (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - What Heat Signifies (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - The Weekend He Died (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - What No One Should Want to Have (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - The Dreamer on the Stone Couch Dreams and Wakes (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - What Is Never Lost (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - The Blue Boy and the Pink Lady (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Casual Neglects (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - Howard Takes the Fifth (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - Jesus Returns (Box 3, Folder 10)
        - Chicken Little (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Who Is Chicken? (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Chicken Slippers (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - Once You Notice Chickens They Are Everywhere (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Chicken Peter (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Chicken Parts (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Poet-Chicken Answers the Interviewer (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Jewish Chicken Examines the Difference between Heaven and Hell (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Like a Chicken (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - Retrieval (Box 3, Folder 20)
        - Spearville, Kansas (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - How William Solomon Invokes Free Will (Box 3, Folder 22)
        - Mary Cassatt’s Twelve Hours in the Pleasure Quarter (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Robert Underhill’s Present (Box 3, Folder 24)
        - Miriam’s Grandmother (Box 3, Folder 25)
        - Singing Miriam’s Lament (Box 3, Folder 26)
        - Maps and Globes (Box 3, Folder 27)
        - Elegy for Hans (Box 3, Folder 28)
        - The Matter of Naming and Counting (Box 3, Folder 29)
        - Leonardo’s Advice to Artists (Box 3, Folder 30)
        - Vermeer’s Lady Reading at an Open Window (Box 3, Folder 31)
        - The Great 14th Street Costume Company (Box 3, Folder 32)
        - Their Places Resolve and Dissolve (Box 3, Folder 33)
        - Victoria’s Secret (Box 3, Folder 34)
        - Dinner before the Blue Horizon (Box 3, Folder 35)
        - Divining Rod (Box 3, Folder 36)
        - I Can’t Remember poem drafts and notes (Box 3, Folder 37)
        - I Can’t Remember manuscript (Box 3, Folder 38-44)
        - I Can’t Remember manuscript with copy edits (Box 3, Folder 45)
        - I Can’t Remember page proofs (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
        - I Can’t Remember uncorrected proof (Box 3, Folder 48)
        - I Can’t Remember copy of dust jacket (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Individual Poems
      Poems in this section are alphabetized by title. Some are also represented in the book collections above, while others do not appear in any other section. Where poem titles changed over the course of subsequent drafts, the folders are named according to Cynthia Macdonald’s labels.
      - A.L. Dismembered (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - ABECEDARIUS: See Acrostic (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - An Academic Solution (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Accidental Causes (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Accomplishments (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Advice Again (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Advice for a Friend Who Is Trying to Give up Smoking from One Who Has Battled Another Addiction (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Advice for the Week (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Advice from the Fulbright Committee (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Advice to an Eighteen Year Old Friend (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Advisability (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Al Fried (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Alien Resident (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Alight (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - All That Glutters Is Not Glut (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - All the Precious Things (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Alternate Means of Transport (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Amazing the Russians Wear Tails (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - American in Japan (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - The Amherst, Houston, New York Triangle (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Amputation (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Anatomy of a Grammar (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - And Cause His Countenance to Shine upon You (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - And That’s the End of the News (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Angles (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Anne (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Another Attempt at the Trick (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Anthropological Exploits (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Apart/A Part (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Apart in Three Parts (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Apartments on First Avenue (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Appearances (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Appearing Presidential (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Applying Instructions from the Manual on Self-Hypnosis (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - An Approach to Self-Reliance (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - As If (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - As Minnows at the Body of a Whale (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - As the Sparks Fly Upward (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Aspects of Unicorns (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - At the Round Earth’s Enduring Corners (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - At the Round Earth’s Imagined Corners: A Stack of Marriage Boxes (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Attempts (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Attics (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Augury (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Auschwitz (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - The B Minor Mass with Flies (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Baby Farming (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - The Balloon (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Battle’s Flower (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Beasts (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - The Beauty Palace (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Beekeeping (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Before the Memorial Sunday (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Behind Trees and in Rooms (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Bends Ends (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Bennington College (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Biloxi, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - A Bird of Parasite (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Birds Rain Down (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - Birthday Message (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Birthmarks (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Black and White and Red All Over (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Black Lines (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Blaze, Climbing Shot Silk and Danse du Feu (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Bloom’s Pulpit (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - A Blow, a Pulsation, an Act of Striking… (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - The Blue Boy and the Pink Lady (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - The Boiling Point (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - Book Report on Report from Engine Company No. 82 by Dennis Smith (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - The Boomerang Nebula (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - The Boy and His Mother Want a Dog (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Breaking Seals (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - BRLEUDE: Purple (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - The Brown Recluse Spider (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - The Bull in the China Shop (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - Burdens (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Burning the Leaf Pile (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Burying the Babies (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - Burying You (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Businessman in Japan (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - The Buzzards (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - By the Sea (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - The Cabinet of the Dead (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Cancer (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - The Cashier Is an Abacist (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Castration Is a Complex Thing (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Casual Cruelties (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - Casual Neglects (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - Caterpillars (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - The Cause (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - Celebrating the Freak (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - The Cell (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - A Certain Distinction (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - Cezanne & Apples (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - Changing (Box 4, Folder 95)
      - Chant of an Old Recluse (Box 4, Folder 96)
      - Chicken and Choke (Box 4, Folder 97)
      - Chicken Examines the Difference between Heaven and Hell (Box 4, Folder 98)
      - Chicken Explores (Box 4, Folder 99)
      - Chicken Family and Meredith Monk (Box 4, Folder 100)
      - Chicken Little (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - Chicken Parts (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - (Chicken Parts) Carving the Chicken (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - Chicken Peter (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - Chicken Slippers (Box 4, Folder 105)
      - Chicken Spring Chicken (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - Chicken Suicide (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - (Chicken) The Lovesong of Chicken Athena (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - Chicken Tribute (Box 4, Folder 109)
      - Chicken with Chicken (Box 4, Folder 110)
      - Chickens in Mahler’s Ninth Symphony (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - Children Who Fall off the Edge of the World Because of Secrets (Box 4, Folder 112)
      - A Child’s Garden of Weeds (Box 4, Folder 113)
      - Chosing the Flock (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - Christmas File Box (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - A Circle of Writers (Box 4, Folder 116)
      - The Circus Flora (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - Cleaning Coffee Pot (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - Climb to the Sun? Puny One (Box 4, Folder 119)
      - Close at the Ear (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - Closing and Opening (Box 4, Folder 121)
      - Cock Robin the Redeemer (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - The Colossal Squid (Box 4, Folder 123)
      - Collecting Matches (Box 4, Folder 124)
      - Coming to a Head (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - A Comparison of Mothers (Box 4, Folder 126)
      - The Concert (Box 4, Folder 127)
      - Conditional (Box 4, Folder 128)
      - Confronting the Toad (Box 4, Folder 129)
      - Congo (Box 4, Folder 130)
      - Conjunctions (Box 4, Folder 131)
      - Connections (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - Consultation (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - Containers (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - Containing (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - Corn in the Bears (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - The Country Club (Box 4, Folder 137)
      - Coupling (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - Course at the American Club (Box 4, Folder 139)
      - Cow in Calf (Box 4, Folder 140)
      - A Cradle of Water (Box 4, Folder 141)
      - A Critical Age (Box 4, Folder 142)
      - Cross Gender (Box 4, Folder 143)
      - The Crucial Moment of Lack (Box 4, Folder 144)
      - Crying through the Soap Operas (Box 4, Folder 145)
      - Cut Off (Box 4, Folder 146)
      - Daiku (Box 4, Folder 147)
      - Dante’s Vancouver (Box 4, Folder 148)
      - The Daughters of Don Francisco Sosa (Box 4, Folder 149)
      - Days of Rain (Box 4, Folder 150)
      - The Dead (Box 4, Folder 151)
      - Dear Friend, Our Shared Fragilities (Box 4, Folder 152)
      - The Death File (Box 4, Folder 153)
      - Death on the High Seas (Box 4, Folder 154)
      - Degrees of Pen/man/ship (Box 4, Folder 155)
      - Departure (Box 4, Folder 156)
      - Depression (Song Lyric) (Box 4, Folder 157)
      - The Dictator Called Himself (Box 4, Folder 158)
      - Dieter’s Journal (Box 4, Folder 159)